Ronald Gustilo

2 Codoniz, Rancho Santa Margarita, CA 92688 | 949.527.549 | rjgustilo@gmail.com

Summary

Work experience at start up, mid-sized, and Fortune 500 companies.

Dynamic, curious, and driven professional with a proven record of leading projects from concept to completion, designing efficient solutions and strategies for business continuity, improving user experience for internal and external stakeholders, and coaching team members to success.

Skills

- Web Development: PHP; CakePHP; Wordpress; Joomla; JQuery; Javascript; HTML; CSS; Apache;
 API
- <u>Database</u>: MySQL; MariaDB; MongoDB
- <u>AWS</u>: EC2; S3; RDS<u>Versioning</u>: SVN; Git
- Server: CentOS; Redhat; Windows Server 2012 R2
- Security: Qualys; ESET Remote Administrator; ESET Safetica; Sonicwall; Sophos
- Virtualization: Virutal Box; VM Ware
- Operating System: Windows 7 and 10; Macintosh
- <u>Software</u>: MS Office; G Suite; Adobe; Salesforce; Egnyte; Confluence; Photoshop; GIMP

Experience

Inco Check Inc.

IT Director

February 2014 – Present

Technology Operations

- Manages overall IT Operations and Infrastructure
- Leads a team of 5 web developers from the junior to senior level
- Facilitates training and development of entry level developers
- Manages IT customer support
- Performs QA of new and custom releases
- Analyze business requirements to determine technological needs
- Assist in software sales presentations to external stakeholders
- Organization's lead software developer
- Manage hardware and software inventory and responsible for hardware and software purchases
- Negotiates contracts and pricing for third party services and subscriptions

Security

- Manages web application and network security
- Manage workstation level security
- Member of security committee
- Facilitates Information Security Awareness training
- Leads government agencies' security audits (IRS and SSA)
- Works with the Director of Fraud Prevention in implementing security controls and company policies

Infrastructure

- Tests and implements technological business continuity plans and disaster recovery steps
- Manages the organization's active directory
- G Suite administrator
- Remote office support
- Reports to the CEO

Inco Check Inc.

Senior Web Developer August 2013 -2014

- Built the company's Quality Control Management and Compliance software used internally and licensed to financial institutions
- Maintain in house PHP application that integrates with government agencies
- Redesigned company website using Joomla

Verizon Wireless

Programmer/Analyst II August 2011 – 2013

- Programmer under the data tools and reporting team
- Develop tools for ad-hoc reporting, features, and functionality for Engineering, Real Estate,
 Operations, Finance, and Executive Management
- Translates user requirements into web-based applications
- Responds to errors and emergencies within applications and programs

Trivedi Foundation

Web Developer/IT Staff November 2010-June 2011

- Built the company's eCommerce website/platform
- Integrated the eCommerce platform with third party CRM and VOIP through API
- Built the company's marketing website
- Trained the customer service department on providing support on the eCommerce platform and CRM usage

VStaff

Web Developer November 2009 – September 2010

- Built CMS websites using PHP, MySQL and Joomla
- Converted layered PSD into Joomla templates
- Experience with Magento Shopping Cart
- Experience with Search Engine Optimization

Education

October 2009

Bachelor in Science Major in Computer Science University of Saint La Salle, Bacolod City, Philippines